Geek Charming is a comedy, drama, family film directed by Jeffrey Hornaday.
Film geek Josh is looking for the subject of his new documentary when a chance meeting
puts the perfect star in his sights—Dylan, his school's most popular junior.
But Dylan's hopes of using the film to become Blossom Queen don't quite match
with Josh's goal to make a hard-hitting exposé about popularity.
Will Josh shoot the film as planned, or show Dylan as
the truly interesting person she is?
Dylan Schoenfield, played by Sarah Hyland.
Josh Rosen, played by Matt Prokop.
Hannah, played by Vanessa Morgan.
Amy Loubalu, played by Sasha Pieterse.
Lola, played by Lili Simmons.
Nicole Paterson, played by Andrea Brooks.
Geek Charming is a 2011 American teen comedy-drama film
released as a Disney Channel Original Movie.
It was directed by Jeffrey Hornaday from a screenplay by Elizabeth Hackett and
Hilary Galanoy, and based on the novel of the same name by Robin Palmer.
The film stars Sarah Hyland and Matt Prokop.
It premiered on November 11, 2011, on Disney Channel, on January 27, 2012, on Disney
Channel (UK & Ireland), and on January 28, 2012, on Disney Channel Asia.
The premiere was watched by 4.9 million viewers, the fifth
largest number for a cable show of that week.
The film explores themes of high school, based on novel or book,
unlikely lovers, documentary filmmaking, teenage romance.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.